# DICKSON DJIDULAH **DJIKUNU**

Ghana, G/A, Dawhenya Abbey, GPS GN07204096 | C: +233 546969778 | ddicksondjikunu@gmail.com

### **SUMMARY**

Resourceful, meticulous IT-oriented person with over 4 years of experience in strategic problemsolving using Information Technologies, system troubleshooting, customer relationship management, software development, general IT equipment maintenance, and management. Team player with strong technical proficiency and commitment to accuracy.

### **SKILLS**

- Programming languages: Python, JavaScript
- Databases: MySQI
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux
- Data Structures and Algorithm

- Web development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Bootstrap, jQuery
- Tools and version control: Git, Visual Studio
- GitHub pages

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Content Manager | ODA Community (My Own Blog and Freelancing)

Remote - December 2022 - Current

- Managed content distribution to online channels and social media platforms.
- Collaborated with graphic designers to create visually appealing graphics that complemented written content effectively.
- Edited and proofread all written materials, maintaining a high standard of grammar and style consistency.
- Utilized analytics and site metrics to determine areas of improvement.
- Image annotation to improve AI metrics for radar systems.
- Tested visual contents on various systems to ensure smooth user experience.

### Municipal Environmental Health Officer | BCMA (Service Personnel)

Eastern Region, Ghana - September 2021 - September 2022

- Inspected businesses for health and safety, food hygiene, and food standards and trouble-shooting equipment problems.
- Followed up on complaints and investigated outbreaks of food poisoning, infectious disease, and pests.
- Collected samples for laboratory testing.
- Enforced environmental health laws in the BCMA areas.
- Investigated accidents at work.
- Advised community groups and gave educational talks.
- Wrote records and reports.

## **Technical Officer | Akim State University College**

Eastern Region, Ghana - August 2017 - September 2021

- Provided technical support and advice for employees and students in need of assistance.
- Designed, developed, and maintained equipment to ensure effective and safe use.
- Serviced and cleaned equipment and infrastructure.
- Tested and evaluated new technologies.
- Worked continuously on tasks until completion and referred to third parties if appropriate.
- Conducted electrical safety tests on computer equipment and other new technology.
- Provided support, including procedural documentation and relevant reports.
- Followed diagrams and written instructions to repair a fault or set up a system.
- Troubleshoot system and network problems, diagnosed and solved hardware and software faults.

### **PROJECTS / ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Designed and developed a store stock management system with HTML, CSS, PHP and JavaScript where a user ads, removes and keep track of stock items as well as generate timely reports.
- Developed a complete full custom e-commerce system featuring admin panel using PHP.
- Designed and developed a comprehensive student portal for educational institution, featuring: student profile management and admissions, course registration and management, fee payment and tracking, result viewing and analysis, notifications, chat and news section.
- Used "mymemory.translated.net API" to develop a text translator.
- Developed a local storage budget tracker with JavaScript.
- Developed pupils' enrollment record system with python, Tkinter and Microsoft Excel.
- Developed and managed wordpress themes and sites.

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science, September 2021

Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology - Kumasi, Ghana

WASSC: Pure Science July 2017

Akim State SHS – E/R Akim Oda, Ghana

#### TRAINING AND CERTIFICATION

- Music Production G-Digital Studio, Weija
- WordPress Development– Udemy

## REFEREE(S)